# **JAKEMILLER**

Full Stack Developer

Santa Barbara, CA (715) 441 1884 jacobkmiller@icloud.com www.jacobkmiller.com

Full Stack Web Developer specializing in back end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in numerous languages including Ruby, Python and Javascript.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby

Rails

TDD

MySQL

**PostgreSQL** 

HTML5

CSS3

Angular.js

Python

Django

Github

Jquery

**Javascript** 

Node.is

Express.js

MongoDB/Mongoose

### **PERSONAL SKILLS**

Fast Learning

Organization

Problem Solvina

Teamwork

Communication

### **EDUCATION**

2009 - 2013

B.A. in Environmental Science

U.C. Santa Barbara

### LINKS

PORTFOLIO

www.jacobkmiller.com

**GITHUB** 

https://github.com/Jacobkmiller

LINKEDIN

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jake-miller-32908445

### **EXPERIENCE**

## FULL STACK DEVELOPER - Intuitive Development Group

(October 2016 - Present)

- Interface with clients to determine project requirements
- Develop custom web applications

### **PYTHON TEACHING ASSISTANT - CODING DOJO**

(December 2016)

- Addressed student questions (Python/Ruby)
- Performed code reviews and demonstrations

# **ENVIRONMENTAL SPECIALIST - ST. CROIX ENVIRONMENTAL** (2013 - 2016)

- Created, edited and analyzed geographic data
- Updated/produced maps for contaminated sites
- Updated/Maintained our geographic database
- Collected data in field such as GPS and water samples

### **PROJECTS**

**StayFYT** (January 2017 – Present)

Link: www.stayfyt.com

**Description:** Web/Mobile App connecting certified personal

trainers with clients

Built With: Ruby on Rails, Angular, Google Maps Javascript API,

JQuery, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, Stripe API

Role:

- Design Database Structure
- Create backend API
- Create Angular Functionality
- Implement Google Maps Javascript API
- Implement Stripe API

### **DOC 2 DOC CONNECT** (October 2016 – Present)

Link: www.doc2docconnect.com

**Description:** Rental Web App Providing a forum for the lending and renting of medical equipment between licensed professionals.

**Built With:** Ruby on Rails, Google Maps Javascript API, JQuery, JQuery UI, PostgreSQL, Materialize, Stripe API

### Role:

- Generate backend functionality
- Implement Google Maps Javascript API
- Customize JQuery UI Datepicker
- Implement Stripe API